Payroll Office; Records ua357
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Payroll Office Records
1916-1986
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua357
1.2 cubic ft.
This collection contains payroll records (salary schedules, payroll guidelines, and other materials from different offices at the University.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
In the first half of the 20th century, payroll activities were administered by the Secretary-Treasurer. As the organization of the University became more complicated, these duties were shifted to a more specialized Payroll Office. Currently, the Payroll Office operates within the Office of Human Resources Management, which is part of the Division of Finance and Administration.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains salary schedules (1916-1917, 1926-1927, 1946-1962), payroll register books (1957-1976), employee health insurance manuals (1977, 1984), state and federal payroll guidelines, and other records relating to payroll management. These materials were created by several different departments: namely the Treasurer (for the earlier years of the collection), the Payroll Office, and other business-related offices.
Arrangement
Collection was maintained in the original order after it was transferred.
College personnel management; Education, Higher--Administration.; Payrolls; payroll records; Administrative records; UAlbany Finance & Business
- Appropriation Charges, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Federal Tax Guides And Memorandum, 1959-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Salary Adjustment for Service, 1954-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Payroll Manual, 1953 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Salary Computation Guide, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Payroll Typing Manual, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Overtime, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- State Tax Guides and Memorandum, 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Student Assistant and Graduate Assistant Stipend tables and Payment Regulations, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Payroll Procedures, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Payroll Procedures, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Dental Insurance Manual, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- State Health Insurance Procedures Manual, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- State Health Insurance Deduction Information, 1967-1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- State Comptroller Payroll Manual, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Personnel Changes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Payroll Register, 1957-1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Payroll Register, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Payroll Register, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Payroll Register, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Payroll Register, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Student Assistant Pay Schedule, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Payroll Procedures, 1945-1956 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Graduate Assistant Payroll, 1966-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Salary Schedules, 1926 July-1927 July (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Salary Schedules, 1916 July-1918 June (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Salary Schedules, 1946-1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Salary Schedules, 1954-1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)